KARTHICK.H

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

karthylock@gmaill.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | AngelList | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Skilled Full-Stack web developer with experience in the full SDLC creating dynamic web applications. An experienced team player with excellent communication and interpersonal skills who has the ability to work independently under pressure can lead, motivate, and influence others

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript (ES6), CSS/SCSS, HTML

Frameworks: React, Bootstrap

Testing: Jest

Databases: PostgreSQL, SQL

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

Other: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

EXPERIENCE

JINNS Software Solutions

Oct 2020 - Present

Full-Stack Developer

The Formula-One — The-Formula-One is a Gym project to collect user details preference. Based on the details and preference it will generate the diet details in a pdf format

• Built with: (Html, CSS, JavaScript, React Js, Ruby, Postgress, Git, Github)

Leads Magnet — Leads Magnet will find leads that will improve your connections to improve your sales.

• Built with: (Html,Css,JavaScript,React Js , Ruby, Postgress ,Git,Github)

Jinns— Company website transferred from one stack to another stack build pixel perfect Ui to showcase the Company's portfolio

• Built with: (Html,Css,JavaScript,React Js ,Git,Github)

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

June 2020 - Month, Year

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program

JINNS Software Solutions

Chennai, India Oct 2020 – Present

Full Stack Developer

- Designed and developed the front-end of web applications with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Worked with platform architects on software optimizations, helping to identify and remove potential bugs and improve performance
- Utilized object-oriented programming while building web application's
- Participated in testing, validation procedures, and documentation
- Worked with SDLC best practices such as continuous integration, unit testing, regression testing, etc. and focused on end to end quality of the product
- Worked collaboratively as a team with fellow developers, sharing ideas to solve complex and challenging business problems

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE June 2020 – Month, 2021

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Learned full-stack web development: git, HTML/CSS, Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React
- Spent over 80 hours learning and using algorithms and data structures
- Worked via remote pair programming 40 hours/week
- Built multiple real-world group projects, combining feedback from mentors through code reviews
- Reviewed other students' pull requests and provided feedback
- Provided general guidance and help to other students

University of Madras

Masters of Computer Applications

April 2019 - April 2021

 Secured 2nd place in Web Designing at National Level Tech Symposium 2019 conducted by Guru Nanak College

University of Madras

Bachelors of Computer Science

June 2016 – April 2019

• Secured 1 st place in Web Designing at National Level Tech Symposium 2018 conducted by Jeppiaar Engineering College

St. George Matriculation Higher Secondary School

June 2015 – April 2016

• Passed HSC Board of Intermediate Education with 65%

St. George Matriculation Higher Secondary School

June 2013 - April 2014

• Passed SSLC Board of Intermediate Education with 82%